Last episode we did our first networking challenge were we first reverse engineered how the server
上一集我们进行了第一次网络挑战，我们首先反向设计了服务器
is listening on a port and then we connected to it with netcat.
正在监听一个端口，然后我们用netcat连接到它。
This video we want to go one layer deeper and have a look at the TCP protocol.
这个视频我们想深入一层，看看TCP协议。
This will be the first time that we have a look at what it means to send a packet over
这将是我们第一次看到发送数据包意味着什么
the network.
网络。
We have used netcat now multiple times.
我们已经多次使用过netcat。
We used it in CTFs and last video to connect to challenges.
我们在CTF和最后一个视频中使用它来连接挑战。
And in the web security series we used it to talk to a real webserver.
在Web安全系列中，我们使用它来与真正的Web服务器对话。
So you know that netcat is a very handy tool to send tcp packets over the network.
所以你知道，netcat是一个非常方便的工具，可以通过网络发送TCP包。
So I suggest we download wireshark to analyse packets we send with netcat.
所以我建议我们下载wireshark来分析我们用netcat发送的数据包。
When we open wireshark we select the network interface we want to capture packets.
当我们打开wireshark时，我们选择要捕获数据包的网络接口。
In this case our traffic doesn’t leave the machine thus we can select the loopback interface.
在这种情况下，我们的流量不会离开机器，因此我们可以选择环回接口。
Loopback is more like a virtual network interface, it’s not a real physical network card stuck
环回更像是一个虚拟的网络接口，它不是一个真正的物理网卡卡住了
in your PC.
在你的电脑里。
Through this interface will go all our traffic that we send around on our local machine.
通过这个接口，我们在本地机器上发送的所有流量都将通过这个接口传输。
And as you may know, the own machine is always identified as localhost or IP 127.0.0.1.
正如您可能知道的，自己的机器总是被标识为localhost或IP 127.0.0.1。
Now let’s use two terminal windows and in one window we start netcat in listening mode
现在让我们使用两个终端窗口，在一个窗口中，我们以监听模式启动netcat。
and we select a port.
我们选择一个端口。
In the other window we can then execute netstat, like in the last video, and we can list all
在另一个窗口中，我们可以执行netstat，就像在最后一个视频中一样，我们可以列出所有
processes that are currently listening on a port.
当前正在侦听端口的进程。
And here is our netcat process.
下面是我们的netcat过程。
You know what, let’s execute our netcat server with strace, so we can see all the
你知道吗，让我们用strace来执行netcat服务器，这样我们就可以看到
syscalls that netcat uses to establish a server.
netcat用于建立服务器的系统调用。
So it will first create a socket, set some options, then bind the port 1234, is now listening
所以它将首先创建一个套接字，设置一些选项，然后绑定端口1234，现在正在监听
on that port and is now waiting for a connection to be established with accept.
在该端口上，正在等待通过accept建立连接。
It’s basically exactly what we reverse engineered in last video.
这基本上就是我们在上一个视频中逆向工程的内容。
We can also quickly check wireshark, and we don’t see any packet being sent over the
我们也可以快速检查wireshark，我们看不到任何数据包通过
network yet.
网络尚未。
Ok.
好啊。
Now let’s use the second window to connect to this netcat server.
现在，让我们使用第二个窗口连接到这个netcat服务器。
You can see on the server that accept now returned, because a client conencted to the
您可以在服务器上看到accept现在返回，因为客户端与
port.
端口。
And now, we see three entries in wireshark.
现在，我们在Wireshark中看到了三个条目。
We see a SYN, SYNACK and ACK. packet.
我们看到一个syn，syn ack和ack。小包裹。
Let’s quickly have a look at those.
让我们快速看一下。
As you can see in the lowest window, a packet is just some binary data.
正如您在最低的窗口中看到的，数据包只是一些二进制数据。
And that binary data has meaning which wireshark can parse and display us nicely.
这个二进制数据意味着wireshark可以很好地解析和显示我们。
So above it we can see the decoded packet and it’s divided by layers.
所以在上面我们可以看到解码后的包，它被层层划分。
Because this packet didn’t leave our machine the ethernet layer is just all zeroes.
因为这个包没有离开我们的机器，所以以太网层都是零。
Usually you would find here your mac address and the mac address from your switch or router.
通常，您可以在这里找到您的MAC地址和来自交换机或路由器的MAC地址。
So that layer is only used between two direct connections.
因此，该层仅用于两个直接连接之间。
Besides the Mac addresses, this layer also contains a TYPE.
除了MAC地址，这个层还包含一个类型。
And the type is set to hex 800, which indicates that the next layer is an IPv4 layer.
类型设置为hex 800，表示下一层是IPv4层。
Wireshark sees that and knows now how to decode the next bytes.
Wireshark看到了这一点，现在知道如何解码下一个字节了。
When you click on the next layer, wireshark will highlight which bytes of the packet belong
单击下一层时，wireshark将突出显示包的哪些字节属于
to that layer.
到那一层。
And you can then see how it is decided that it is an IP v4, version 4 layer, because the
然后您可以看到它是如何决定它是一个IPv4，版本4层的，因为
first 4 bits of this byte is 4.
这个字节的前4位是4。
You can also see here the source and destination IP, which in this case is the same.
您还可以在这里看到源IP和目标IP，在本例中是相同的。
So while the ethernet layer with mac addresses was about direct connections, the IP layer
因此，当带有MAC地址的以太网层是关于直接连接时，IP层
can contain an address very far away on the internet, and the switches will make sure
在互联网上可以包含一个非常远的地址，并且交换机将确保
that this packet is forwarded until you reach that machine.
直到你到达那台机器，这个包才被转发。
This layer also contains information about the layer afterwards, and that is the protocol
这个层还包含了关于层的信息，这就是协议
identifier.
标识符。
In this case it’s 6, which means the content of this IP layer is a TCP header.
在本例中，它是6，这意味着这个IP层的内容是一个TCP头。
IP and TCP are usually always together, it’s very common, thus you have probably heard
IP和TCP通常在一起，这很常见，因此您可能听说过
of TCP/IP before, which just says that there is a TCP layer over an IP layer.
在TCP/IP之前，它只是说在IP层上有一个TCP层。
So the ethernet layer helped to get from machine to machine, the IP layer helped to identify
因此，以太网层有助于从一台机器到另一台机器，IP层有助于识别
which machine is the real destination of this, the TCP layer will now help identify which
TCP层现在将帮助识别
program or process on this machine should handle this packet.
这台机器上的程序或进程应该处理这个包。
And that is identified with the port number.
并用端口号标识。
You can see here that the destination port is set to 1234.
您可以在这里看到目标端口设置为1234。
You can also see here a source port, which is required so you can receive answers from
您还可以在这里看到一个源端口，这是必需的，这样您就可以从
this server.
这个服务器。
So when the server responds with a packet, it will use this port, so that the client
所以当服务器用一个包响应时，它将使用这个端口，这样客户端
machine knows which process gets this response.
机器知道哪个进程得到这个响应。
And that’s usually a random high port number.
这通常是一个随机的高端口号。
Anyhow, now we understand how a full TCP packet is constructed, now let’s have a look at
不管怎样，现在我们了解了完整的TCP包是如何构造的，现在让我们来看看
the protocol.
协议。
A Protocol just refers to a set of rules on how to talk to another computer.
协议只是指一组关于如何与另一台计算机对话的规则。
If a client and server agree on how to send data back and forth, it will work.
如果客户机和服务器就如何来回发送数据达成一致，它将工作。
So What we will see now is just what somebody came up with in order to create a data connection.
所以我们现在看到的就是有人为了创建一个数据连接而想到的。
Just remember, at the moment we have not sent any data with netcat, so far we only established
请记住，目前我们还没有向netcat发送任何数据，到目前为止，我们只建立了
a connection.
连接。
Ok, so we see that 3 packets were exchanged.
好的，我们看到交换了3个包。
First the client sent a so called SYN packet, a synchronize packet.
首先，客户机发送了一个所谓的SYN包，一个同步包。
And then the server responded with an SYN,ACK packet.
然后服务器用一个syn，ack包响应。
Meaning I acknowledge that I received it.
意思是我承认我收到了它。
This is important because maybe the initial packet didn’t arrive.
这很重要，因为可能最初的数据包没有到达。
So when you as a client get a response, you know that the server got your message.
因此，当您作为客户机得到响应时，您知道服务器收到了您的消息。
This means the client knows now that the connection works.
这意味着客户机现在知道连接可以工作了。
But from the perspective of the server the server doesn’t know yet if the sending the
但是从服务器的角度来看，服务器还不知道发送
packet was successful.
数据包成功。
Maybe the server can only receive but not send packets.
也许服务器只能接收但不能发送数据包。
Thus the client will respond to the SYN,ACK packet with an ACK packet, acknowledging that
因此，客户机将用一个ACK包响应SYN、ACK包，确认
it got the servers answer and now both parties are sure, YES I successfully exchanged packets
它得到了服务器的回答，现在双方都确定，是的，我成功地交换了数据包
with this other machine, now we can talk data.
用另一台机器，现在我们可以谈数据了。
And this is all done transparently.
这一切都是透明的。
You didn’t have to construct these packets yourself.
您不必自己构建这些包。
You simply opened a socket and waited for a connection.
您只需打开一个插座并等待连接。
Ok.
好啊。
Now let’s send some data from the client to the server.
现在让我们将一些数据从客户机发送到服务器。
You can see that immediately the server was able to read the line you sent.
您可以立即看到服务器能够读取您发送的行。
How does that look in wireshark.
这在Wireshark中是怎么看的？
We see two new packets.
我们看到两个新的包。
A PSH packet from the client to the server, and an ack packet back.
从客户机到服务器的PSH数据包，以及返回的ACK数据包。
The packet from the client also now has an additional DATA layer.
来自客户机的数据包现在也有一个额外的数据层。
And that data layer just contains the raw bytes we sent.
数据层只包含我们发送的原始字节。
And the server responds with an ack, to inform the client that the packet was succesfully
服务器用ACK响应，通知客户端包成功
received.
收到。
Now let’s send a response from the server.
现在让我们从服务器发送一个响应。
You see, the server simply wrote the text to the filedescriptor 4, which is the filedescriptor
你看，服务器只是把文本写到文件描述符4，它是文件描述符
that accept returned.
接受返回。
As you can see, an application simply writes to that paseudo file, that socket, and the
如您所见，应用程序只需写入该paseudo文件、该套接字和
magic below sent that over the network.
下面的魔法通过网络发送了。
Now let’s have a look what it did, It also just sent a PSH packet and the client
现在让我们看看它做了什么，它还发送了一个psh包和客户机
acknwoledged the arrival with an ack packet back.
用一个ACK包将到达的货物打包回去。
One more more thing.
还有一件事。
Obviously the size of a packet is limited.
显然，数据包的大小是有限的。
So what happens when you send a lot of data, let’s say you upload a huge file somewhere,
所以当你发送大量数据时会发生什么，比如说你上传了一个巨大的文件，
how will that work?
那怎么办？
Let’s just copy a bunch of characters and send them.
让我们复制一些字符并发送它们。
Ahhh, see, now there are more than just two packets.
啊，看，现在有两个以上的包。
You don’t see it when you develop an application, but somwhere in the kernel, network card or
在开发应用程序时，您不会看到它，但在内核、网卡或
driver, I don’t really know, it got split up.
司机，我真的不知道，它被分开了。
You can also see that the second packet was not sent along with the first one, the second
您还可以看到第二个包没有与第一个包一起发送，第二个包
packet was only sent out once the server acknowledges the first one.
只有当服务器确认第一个包时，才会发送该包。
Let’s see what happens when you kill the client.
让我们看看当你杀死客户时会发生什么。
Even though we just ctrl+c netcat, we can see in wireshark, that FIN packet was sent
即使我们只是ctrl+c netcat，我们也可以在wireshark中看到，fin包已经发送了
out, do indicate we are done with this channel.
out，do表示我们已经完成了这个频道。
You can free up your resources and you don’t have to expect more packets from this connection.
您可以释放您的资源，并且不必期望来自此连接的更多数据包。
And like during setup, there are 3 packets exchanged.
和安装过程一样，有3个包交换。
The server acknowledges the fin by the client, now the client knows, that the server knows
服务器通过客户机确认fin，现在客户机知道，服务器知道
that it is done.
完成了。
but the server doesn’t know yet if the client knows that it knows it’s done, so it also
但是服务器还不知道客户机是否知道它已经完成了，所以它也
responds with an ack.
用ACK响应。
Now both now that it’s over.
现在都结束了。
Now this whole exchange is referred to as a TCP stream.
现在整个交换被称为TCP流。
We established a connection, then exchanged data back and forth, and then quit the connection.
我们建立了一个连接，然后来回交换数据，然后退出连接。
And wireshark allows us to investigate this stream, for example with Follow TCP stream.
wireshark允许我们研究这个流，例如使用follow tcp流。
Here only the data is visible and color coded who sent what.
这里只有可见的数据和发送内容的颜色编码。
And now you should watch my HTTP protocol video from the web security series because
现在您应该从Web安全系列中观看我的HTTP协议视频，因为
you will understand now much better what it means to have a server and client.
现在您将更好地理解拥有服务器和客户机意味着什么。
And that HTTP is just data sent over TCP, exactly how we sent these messages.
HTTP只是通过TCP发送的数据，正是我们发送这些消息的方式。
A browser and a webserver are just special programs that do special things with special
浏览器和Web服务器只是一些特殊的程序，它们用特殊的
messages received over TCP.
通过TCP接收的消息。